Привет, Фрэнс!
Велкам-ту-привет, русский!
Эписот 51.
Итс второе июля 2026 года.
Ам Олья.
Today's lesson is going to be a fun one.
Поехали.
Орвортов дадей из кошка.
Кошка.
Сэйт слолый возьми.
Этминс кат.
Сынгов кошка.
А зеркозика.
Очкотетку.
Рылингаб.
Форанап.
Мая кошка любит молоко.
Датминс Майкат likes milk.
Репит авторми.
Кошка.
На let's build more animal words.
Орферсный ворт из собака.
Сабака.
Это means dog.
Репит авторми.
Сабака.
Сабака бежит в парке.
The dog runs in the park.
Мэмарихук.
Sounds like soul back.
Your dog comes back when you call.
Некст вехав птица.
Птица.
Это means bird.
Репит авторми.
Птица.
Птица поет на дереве.
The bird sings in the tree.
Мэмарихук.
Птиц like the tweet of a bird.
Our next word is riba.
Райба.
It means fish.
Репит авторми.
Рыба.
Рыба плавает в воде.
The fish swims in the water.
Мэмарихук.
Рыба.
Раем светы.
Имажена рыба свемимбай.
На уметь медведь.
Мед-вед.
It means bear.
Репит авторми.
Медведь.
Большой и сильный.
Добер из бег и строго.
Мэмарихук.
Медведь.
Sounds like mud wet.
Обер.
Датмайт.
From a few lessons ago.
It means my.
Now you can say.
Майя кошка.
Майя кошка тк.
Майкет.
Example sentence.
Майя кошка.
Синья сегодня.
Example translation.
Майкет.
Изблю today.
Мэмарихук.
Ремембр.
Майя from earlier lessons.
It means my.
Ремембр.
Дом from earlier.
It means house.
Орхом.
Кошка в доме.
The cat is in the house.
Мэмарихук.
Дом like.
Дом.
Your.
Let's look at one simple grammar idea.
Russian nouns have gender that affect endings.
Кошка ends in a.
Они ошла вюд.
So it is feminine.
Саблака is also feminine.
Медведь ends in a consonant.
So it is masculine compared to English.
Where the cat stays the same no matter what.
In Russian the word itself changes slightly with articles we don't even have.
In Russian fairy tales.
Animals often talk and help children.
Like the clever fox or the vice bear in stories by pushkin.
Russian love keeping cats as pets because they are seen as symbols of comfort and good luck in the home.
Now it is practice time.
For kids draw your favorite animal and write its Russian name underneath.
Then show it to a grown-up and say the word out loud.
For adults look at a pet photo or zoo picture and describe it using three new words.
For example,
моя кошка or рыба в воде.
Now hear something really cool about one of today's words.
Did you know the Russian word кошка and the English word cat are actually cousins
that both trace back to the same ancient route.
This word started in North Africa or the Middle East with the sound keep or keep.
Travel through Latin cactus, then into many European languages and finally reach the Russian as кошка.
But be careful, the Russian word code is the masculine form for a male cat while кошка
is usually for a female cat or cat in general.
Next time you see a cat, remember its Russian cousin.
кошка comes from the same ancient meow sound route.
That connection is your secret shortcut to remember it forever.
That means well done.
Remember every expert started as a beginner practicing today's words out loud,
even just once and you will be amazed how fast you learn.
See you next time.
Пока.
That's Russian for bye.
And if you'd rather watch then listen.
Find us on YouTube at nearer as.
Are you linked in the show notes?
Этот выпуск озвучен с помощью EE синтеза голоса.
Подбор тем и анализ остается за человеком.